# Mark Ryan Guamos

## Software Engineer

Metro Manila, PH

A Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of professional experience, specializing in fullstack development, Java, SQL, and Javascript. A proven track record of managing large scale software engineering projects to support cloud deployments and integrations.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Backend Frontend DevOps** Java Spring Boot SQL JPA Javascript Typescript React Docker Kubernetes CI/CD AWS ArgoCD Hibernate MyBatis Nats Vue Angular **TailwindCSS** Selenium Message Queue Pub/Sub HTML5 Playwright Websocket

#### **Others**

Blockchain Solidity Web3

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE (7)**

Software Engineer at Amihan Solutions

Jul 2022 - Current

#### Philippines,

- Responsible for application maintenance across the codebase.
- Responsible for adding new features in the application.
- Did application integration with clients and third-party providers.
- Did application support for multiple clients.
- Utilized AWS cloud services.

#### Software Engineer at Shang Software Solutions

Nov 2017 - Jun 2022

#### Makati,

- Improved existing applications and fixed concurrency issues.
- Automated processes and regression tests using Selenium/Appium/Playwright.
- Developed monitoring tools.
- Developed online payment gateway (kind of).
- Utilized DevOps tools like CI/CD, Docker, and Kubernetes.
- Participated on migrating on-premise applications to Azure.

#### Software Engineer at Yondu, Inc.

Aug 2016 - Oct 2017

- Responsible for application maintenance and SQL optimizations.
- Mentored some developers on fullstack development.
- Did application revamp.

- Led a small team of developers.
- Developed a Legal Case Management System for a gov't agency.
- Mentored some junior developers.

#### Software Engineer at New World Solutions Ltd

Jan 2013 - Nov 2014

- Responsible for application maintenance across the codebase.
- Responsible for adding new features in the application.
- Assisted with QA testing.

#### Software Engineer at ODGS

Jan 2012 - Jan 2013

### Makati,

- Responsible for application maintenance across the codebase.
- Responsible for adding new features in the application.
- Did application support.

#### **Software Engineer** at AATi Technologies

Nov 2010 - Sep 2011

- Helped with small bug fixes while learning Java and several Java frameworks.
- Developed a small tool that parses handwritten values in a scanned form using OCR.

#### **EDUCATION (1)**

Bachelor of Science Information Technology at International Electronics and Technical Institue

2006 - 2010

#### **INTERESTS**

